<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home page? on hbina page</title><link>https://hbina.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home page? on hbina page</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hbina.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Human (Dis)connection</title><link>https://hbina.github.io/human_disconnection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hbina.github.io/human_disconnection/</guid><description>I had a memory from when I was growing up that I am not even sure is real or not. The memory is that of staring at myself in the mirror and realizing that the person in the mirror is &amp;ldquo;me&amp;rdquo;. It was a very stark moment of realization for me that &amp;ldquo;that is me, that will always be me. That&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rdquo;. I remember staring at the mirror for quite some, Of course, I know that other people exist, and that they are living and interacting iamong each other.</description></item><item><title>A Retrospective on The Humble Programmer by Edsger W. Dijkstra</title><link>https://hbina.github.io/humble_programmer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hbina.github.io/humble_programmer/</guid><description>The article is freely available here or at the bottom where I have also copied the transcript below for prosperity. It is crazy to think how much foresight he had 50 years ago.
The increased power of the hardware, together with the perhaps even more dramatic increase in its reliability, made solutions feasible that the programmer had not dared to dream about a few years before. And now, a few years later, he had to dream about them and, even worse, he had to transform such dreams into reality!</description></item><item><title>Writing a basic redis clone in Go from scratch</title><link>https://hbina.github.io/redis_clone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hbina.github.io/redis_clone/</guid><description>Introduction In this tutorial, we will write a basic redis server that is capable of responding to valid RESP requests. In case you are not familiar with what redis is, check out their website. Needless to say, it is an extremely popular caching mechanism that is used everywhere.
However, you might think to yourself that implementing one is a daunting task. I am going to show you that (minus all the critical performance requirements), a redis server is in fact pretty simple.</description></item><item><title>althttpd: From Top to Bottom</title><link>https://hbina.github.io/althttp_from_top_to_bottom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hbina.github.io/althttp_from_top_to_bottom/</guid><description>Before Venturing Further&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s nice to have the codebase open as reference. Each chapters will cover mostly 1 function and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go through every single bit. Just the parts that I find interesting. I will cover the global variables as we go through.
Sometimes there will be backtracking and jumping ahead of the source code as I see necessary.
Please read about the design philosophy here.
Check out the source code here.</description></item></channel></rss>